The butterfly perches on a horn!
Search for gold until you're torn!
Smash it!
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.
For those of you who have just arrived,
welcome to Bondan's Trance School party.
Today, we're invoking
the butterfly spirit,
the mouse deer spirit,
and the horse spirit.
For those of you who wish to be possessed,
please approach us.
Today's trance leader is Mr. Yoga Nugraha.
You may also approach his assistants,
Pawit Arifin, who is playing the guitar,
or Bayu Laksana, who is playing the flute.
And of course, we have a mantra today.
In the hallucination realm,
everything is under the care
of our trance school leader,
Mr. Bondan Junaedi.
We would also like to thank
the head of Sentum Village
for inviting Bondan's Trance School
from Latas Village
to celebrate
Sentum Village's successful harvest.
Please join us,
don't just stay on the sidelines.
Come to the middle.
If you have been fasting,
come and experience the butterfly spirit.
This spirit is not just any spirit.
It was conjured up
straight from Latas Village's spring.
The spirit will bring color to your lives,
ladies and gentlemen.
A meadow full of flowers.
Go ahead and give it a try.
If you haven't fasted,
but have been doing this for a while,
you may also join in, don't be shy.
Together, let's forget for a second
about work, loans, family problems.
Enter the hallucination realm
and let it all go.
Be one with the butterfly spirit.
Just like that.
Before I forget,
let's also welcome Guru Asri,
the leader of the Central Trance School.
Welcome to our trance party, ma'am.
Why did you stop?
I'm looking for a new spirit channeler.
Keep going.
Send her into the hallucination realm.
Good. She's in.
Now, just like a butterfly spirit,
extract the nectar from the flowers,
and let them drink.
Nectar, nectar, nectar.
Don't screw this up.
Nectar…
- Nectar…
- Concentrate.
- Focus on what the nectar looks like.
Does he know what he's doing?
Nectar, nectar, nectar.
Sausages. Damn it!
Are you dumb?
If you want a sausage, you can have one.
But don't bring them
into the hallucination realm.
Focus!
Nectar, nectar, sweet nectar.
Nectar, nectar, nectar.
Eggs!
Think nectar, not eggs.
It's a butterfly spirit,
not a snake spirit!
You can't even concentrate,
and you expect to be a spirit channeler?
Nectar, nectar, nectar.
Don't turn into oil.
Nectar, nectar…
Oil!
You're hurting them. Back off!
Oil burns the heart!
Turn it into nectar!
Please forgive my student, ma'am.
Bayu, you idiot. Get out of here!
You can try again tomorrow.
May I have your attention,
ladies and gentlemen?
We are accepting donations
and contributions
to stop Wanaria
from getting their hands on our spring.
Thanks, sir. I'm just heading over there.
- Thank you so much!
- Bayu, where are you going?
Miss.
You were at the party, right?
I'd like to apologize.
Were you hurt?
That was supposed to be nectar, not oil.
Here, I got you this voucher
as a little compensation.
- A voucher?
- Yes, you can use it for the next party.
You won't have to pay for the entrance.
Just show them the butterfly tattoo.
Can I also get your phone number
for our customer records?
When does this voucher expire?
I may already be back in Jakarta by then.
That's not a problem.
Jakarta is only two hours away from Latas.
- 081…
- Yes?
723…
- You're not gonna write it down?
- I'll remember.
- Seriously?
- Yes.
081723857533.
0817…
23857533.
- You're good.
- It's nothing.
Sure you won't forget it?
081723857533.
Can I also have your name?
I'll only tell you my name
if I get well compensated as a customer.
Shit! Bayu, help! He's getting away!
Thank you for coming
to Bondan's Trance School party.
Take care!
- Bayu!
- 081723857533.
- Yes, yes, yes.
Did you forget the rules?
We can't let the spirit hosts get away.
Play!
081723857533.
Was that a lotto number? Come on!
- Guru Asri had her eye on me today.
- Don't get your hopes up.
"Bayu Prasetya, featured by Asri's
Trance School, number one in Latas!"
"Bayu Prasetya,
featured by Tono's Trance School,
number 2000-964-33-267…"
Shut up,
I'm trying to memorize her number!
- 0817238…
- Seven! Three, two! One, one!
Shut up.
Hey, look!
They're turning your house into a hotel!
And your house has been turned
into a golf course!
You could use the money for your wedding!
What a waste! Might as well
get a new pedal for my guitar!
Asshole!
- Go to hell, you bum!
- I am a bum.
So, you can't use grasshoppers
as bait for catfish?
No, we usually use tree worms.
When it comes to snails,
we use feces as bait.
- Really?
- I mean human feces.
Hey, Bayu.
Mr. Fahri, this is my son.
- Hello, Bayu. I'm Fahri.
- My hands are dirty.
It's all right.
Dirty is another word for organic.
You haven't been
catching snails, have you?
- No.
- All good?
- We'd better get going now.
- Okay.
- Mr. Iwan, thank you for your time.
- Sure.
- Keep me posted.
- Will do.
- I'm serious.
- Yes.
I'll be back next week
and I'll bring my rod.
I'll learn how to fish from you,
the fishing master.
Stop it. I just do it for fun.
Bye, Bayu. See you.
- Drive safe.
- Let's go.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
What did he want?
Nothing, he just wanted
to ask me some questions about our land.
- Why?
- Because of this.
A new real estate project.
They're building houses
closer to our area.
- Where are we going to live then?
- Here.
A brand new apartment building
close to the train station.
You wanna go back to Jakarta?
Back to eating once every two days?
Well, a friend of mine
asked me to join her business.
Bottled water dispensers.
We'll break even in no time.
What if it fails, like the silver jewelry
business you had with your other friend?
I ended up working as a street performer.
It's still under discussion.
Just relax and eat something.
I have to fast.
I'm getting ready to catch some spirits.
Catch spirits? You're a musician.
Guru Asri came to the trance party today.
She saw me play and seemed interested.
From the Central Trance School?
So you'll get paid better?
I have to be selected first.
That's why I need to practice
for tomorrow.
I thought you wanted to eat every day,
but now you're fasting willingly.
- I don't get it.
- The difference is now it's my choice.
In Jakarta, it was because
debt collectors were stalking us.
Don't sell the house, okay?
This is my chance to earn a living here.
After this,
I'll be able to provide for you.
I'm not gonna suffer again in Jakarta.
This company
is trying to buy Mr. Dawuri's
spirit spring and turn it into a hotel.
That means no more spirits.
No more trance parties.
No more jobs for us.
The problem is,
Mr. Dawuri has a grandson
with brain cancer.
They need 250 million rupiah
for his surgery.
Wanaria has offered him
300 million for his spring.
Our trance school has negotiated
for 250 million.
Thankfully, Mr. Dawuri agreed.
So, next month,
Central Trance School will have
a big fundraising trance party.
And we need a new spirit channeler.
He has to be the best in Latas,
because they convinced
our previous spirit channeler
to sell his land and move to Jakarta.
Form a circle for the host!
Forming the circle!
This baby monkey spirit needs comforting.
Whoever gets the monkey
to hug the wooden beam, wins.
You're all spirit-channeler candidates.
Can you make this host feel good?
Get ready!
Begin!
Concentrate.
Focus.
Draw him toward your sound.
Like all living beings,
humans also need to hug each other.
At least six times a day.
Hugging reduces stress
and makes you live longer.
Be a fluffy stuffed animal.
No matter how big or small
this village's problems are,
as long as we hug each other,
we'll overcome all of them!
Problems.
Dad is going to sell the house to Wanaria.
Shut up!
We'll be homeless again.
Focus.
Concentrate.
After they buy the house,
they'll tear it down.
This is all Fahri's fault.
Focus.
Get rid of all the anger and resentment.
Achieving a state of trance
is all about channeling happiness.
Be happy, be joyful, be grateful.
Be hugged by the stuffed animal.
Two musicians are fighting
for the monkey's hug.
The baby monkey
can sense who's the most comforting,
who can make him feel safest,
who can give him the most warmth,
who can best protect him from evil beings.
This will show us
who's got the purest heart.
We'll feel the love you all have to give.
Focus all your love,
visualize it, and let it out!
Channel it!
Stop!
For tomorrow,
you have to bring a spirit and a host.
Do you have them?
- No, ma'am.
- Go find them, then.
Do it tonight.
Remember,
you have to be one with the spirit.
- Got it?
- Got it, ma'am.
Getting a head start
for the selection, I see.
Excuse us, Mr. Dawuri.
We're looking for some spirits.
Go ahead!
What's Wanaria doing here?
You think Mr. Dawuri will cave in?
Wanaria offers good money.
It's up to his family, I guess.
The one at the spring, monitor?
Let's go down to the other spring.
No one's there yet.
Should I send you some coffee?
Those assholes from Wanaria are too close.
But if you focus,
you'll still be able to catch the spirit.
Ready?
First, visualize the throne.
Has it been connected
to the battery yet, sir?
Can you see a white throne?
Invite the spirit to sit on the throne.
Come on.
Relax.
Concentrate.
Mouse deer team, do you copy?
Mouse deer team here, go ahead.
Have you memorized Wanaria's song?
You need to know it by Monday.
Okay, we're going to rehearse it.
Can you play it to us, sir?
Copy that.
Okay, I just got it. Playing it now.
Life is better in the land of Wanaria
We'll protect it until the end of time
The Mighty Guard, that's us
My body and soul…
Concentrate.
Ignore those voices.
Focus on your breathing.
Focus. Turn off all your senses.
Focus, focus, focus. Don't get distracted.
Ignore the smells. Ignore the voices.
Remember,
you have to be one with the spirit.
A turtle?
Pawit, help me.
Become a turtle.
A turtle inside its shell.
Inside its shell,
a turtle can't hear anything.
a turtle can't see anything.
Inside its shell, a turtle feels safe.
The throne is clear.
I'm ready to receive the spirit.
Did you catch it?
Did you catch it or not?
Excuse me, miss.
Bondan's Trance School
wants to give you this free chicken soup
as an apology for what happened
the other day.
Are you blind? This is a chicken farm.
If the chickens smell that soup,
they'll go nuts.
- Really?
- Who let you in?
- I'm calling security.
- I'm sorry! I didn't know!
I'm just kidding, chill.
Damn.
You think you're a comedian, don't you?
I have another voucher for you.
Another voucher?
What are you, an online shop?
This is a VIP voucher.
You get free access to our rehearsal
and sound check.
Do you work as a K-pop event
promoter or something?
No, not K-pop.
What other trance parties
have you attended?
Bondan,
Tono…
What's the other one? Oh! Wati.
Only those three.
The school I'm with now
is the best of them all.
I'd like to invite you
to be my practice partner.
I'll give you free tickets to parties.
- For real?
- Yeah.
When?
Tomorrow.
Okay.
Really?
Awesome.
But 12 hours before, you have to…
Fast. I know.
So what's the soup for, then?
Good question.
Can I have your name?
It's for the guest book
for tomorrow's party.
Asking for customers' names, again?
Is it a school or a coffee shop?
Here.
All right.
Thank you, Laksmi. I'm Bayu.
See you then.
See you tomorrow, Laksmi.
- Yes.
- See you.
- Bayu.
- I'm heading out, Dad.
- This is an old friend of mine.
- Hello, handsome.
- Bayu.
Excuse me, ma'am.
I have to go to work. Goodbye.
Wait, Bayu. I have a present for you.
Ta-da!
Isn't it great?
For you to practice.
Practice for what?
When your father opens his water
dispenser business in Jakarta,
you can use this motorcycle
to deliver the bottles.
Water bottles?
Your father said Wanaria
has made him an offer on this house.
It's good money.
It's just an idea, Bayu.
Thanks, ma'am,
but I already have a job here
and I'm not planning to leave.
- Dad, where's my bike?
- Mrs. Nana's son took it for a ride.
Take the motorcycle. It's faster.
Let me show you.
Don't knock it until you've tried it.
You'll like it.
Okay? Here you go.
Mouse deer on a small tree branch!
Pay your debt and leave nothing to chance!
Concentrate.
Come on, focus.
Channel the joy.
Don't think about anything else.
Mr. Damar, Mrs. Rosita,
and Mr. Prapto are with us today.
They are former spirit channelers
who will be the judges for the selection.
We will be evaluating your performance.
There are 20 spirits in this village.
If you're not sure
about the spirit you have now,
replace it with another one.
Sorry. A Wanaria bulldozer
was blocking the road.
It's fine.
- Tutik from Maryana.
- What's your spirit?
The finch, ma'am.
Perched on the rain gutter it tweets!
A sweet tweet! A sweet tweet!
Play something more soothing
and melodious. Don't lose it.
Today, there are eight candidates
from eight schools in Latas.
The two candidates with the lowest scores
will be eliminated.
The top three candidates
will move on to the final selection.
Hey, kid.
What's your name, again?
That's right, Bayu!
- That's me.
- Yes.
I saw you yesterday.
That was amazing.
Amazing how bad you suck.
- Record me, will you?
- Sure.
I am Ananto from Ningsih's school!
- What's your spirit?
- The ant.
Fire ant! Burn! Burn! Burn!
His hair will return!
Teachers and spirit channelers
work as one.
The teachers create the realm,
and the spirit channelers
bring it to life.
Next!
I'm Bayu from Bondan's school.
- What's your spirit?
- The turtle.
Geez.
Don't be rude.
What's wrong with bringing
the most basic spirit?
Even my kid in grade school
can get that one.
No wonder he was late.
He's as slow as a turtle.
Don't mind them. They don't mean any harm.
Those percussionists
have looked after me since I was a kid.
Okay, I'll create a special place
for Bayu the Turtle.
The turtle wrapped around a whale!
Hard-shelled, soft as hair!
The turtle
tucks itself into its shell to rest.
How will you, Bayu the Turtle,
make the host feel comfortable
inside that shell?
Tough as a rattan tree!
Let's see how thick the turtle's shell is.
You can hit her all you want.
As long as the turtle's in its shell,
it'll feel like a gentle massage to her.
Someone's getting distracted.
Focus on massaging Laksmi.
Don't think about anything else.
Shit.
Hello, Bayu.
What's on your mind, boy?
Focus!
If your thoughts waver,
she could actually get caned.
Concentrate. Dad won't remarry.
Bayu?
Your tune is shaky.
Get rid of all made-up thoughts.
Dad won't run a water dispenser business
with Mrs. Nana.
Come, my boy.
Help mama refill the water bottle.
If your mind wanders off,
that girl could get hurt!
Focus, focus, focus.
Stay in the hallucination realm.
Come, my boy.
Help mama refill the water bottle.
- Laksmi!
- Wait!
Laksmi!
The sound of your flute tells me
you're having family problems.
We keep no secrets in this school.
We can help you resolve
your concentration issues.
Now, tell me honestly.
What were you thinking about?
Tell me.
I was thinking about my father.
What about your father?
My father wants me to get married.
Liar, liar.
If I can hear your tune wavering,
your lies are also clear to my ears.
Tell me the truth!
My father…
wants me to move to Jakarta
and help with his water business.
- With what money?
- A loan from the bank.
Liar, liar.
You already lied twice, boy!
You don't think I can see through it?
A liar is someone
who can't accept who he is.
So how can he channel spirits
for other people?
He'll get the money…
by selling the house.
- Traitor!
- Wanaria's pet!
Why did your father
have to resort to selling the house?
He doesn't have a job.
No one will hire him.
Why is that?
He stole a phone and went to jail.
What does your mother do?
She married a picture framer.
Is she happy with that man?
Yes!
Is your father happy?
No!
Are you happy?
If you're not happy, do you think
you can channel happiness for others?
No!
Can you change the past?
Have you made peace with the past?
No!
If you're not at peace with the past,
how can you be happy?
Judges,
who got the highest score today?
Ananto got the highest score.
The bottom two were Sulis…
And Sigit.
Make peace with what has happened.
If you can't do that, you can forget
about becoming a spirit channeler.
Just help your father with his business.
Or sell picture frames,
like your stepfather.
That one goes to the right,
and I want that one on the left.
- Yes, it has more space now.
- That one looks good there.
This isn't what I want.
Okay.
Bayu.
We might never get
another opportunity like this.
We can't always depend
on Uncle Rahmat's monthly allowance.
If the water business goes well,
you won't have to suffer like now.
Suffer? I actually enjoy
working at the trance school.
And I can still afford
to buy us food every day.
I've been buying enough food
for three meals a day.
But it's always the same food.
Don't you want to live more comfortably?
You want to eat something different?
Fine, I'll get it for you.
I have to fast anyway.
I only eat once a day.
What more do you want?
In the city, we'll have to live
in a tiny, stuffy place.
If you fail,
the debt collectors will come.
You'll take out more loans
and drown in debt.
Listen, if we move to the city,
you can pursue your dream
and study hospitality.
I don't want that anymore.
I'll be a spirit channeler
at Asri's school.
I'll make as much money
as Nana's business.
Tell Uncle Rahmat
not to send any more money next month.
What if you don't get selected?
There are a lot of people
who are better than you.
I will be selected!
I've been practicing for years.
Don't ruin what I've accomplished so far.
But I'm not the only owner of this house.
It's also Uncle Rahmat's and Aunt Wati's.
Your grandmother split it among us.
Fine, then don't say anything.
Don't tell them about Fahri's offer.
We can use my spirit-channeler salary
to pay off the house
so it can be all ours.
How long will you be out catching spirits?
Next week, we have to go to Jakarta
to see Rahmat's new granddaughter.
Yes, I know.
Just don't tell them anything.
The goat, the bedbug and the grasshopper
are mid-rank spirits in Latas.
To catch them, one must suffer,
fast, and live like those animals do.
The more we behave like them,
the faster they will come to us.
Empty, empty, empty.
Calm, calm, calm.
Relax, relax, relax.
Get out of my head. Get out of my head.
Noisy, noisy, noisy.
Blood rushes to the head.
Relax.
My mind is empty.
I'm ready to receive the spirit.
Hello.
What kind of meditation technique
are you practicing?
Sorry, but you will have to move
because we're cutting down the trees.
I'm sorry.
That new spirit feels good.
I didn't think I could get possessed
without Guru Asri's mantra.
But the realm is just black.
There aren't any colors.
I thought you wouldn't want to practice
with the son of a thief
who hurt you not once but twice.
Whatever.
One day, when you become a trance master,
I will be able to say,
"He's a master thanks to me."
Shut up.
Do you prefer Jakarta or this place?
I like it here, of course.
My dad got scammed by his friend
in Jakarta.
Dad lost everything.
Mom left him. We were starving.
Hey, that kind of rhymes.
Dad lost everything.
Mom left him. We were starving.
And your head was spinning.
I had to drop out of vocational school.
I did all kinds of odd jobs.
Check it out.
I did a gig as a silver human statue.
I was a clown once.
I even begged for money.
But when my dad got arrested,
I came back here to live with my grandma.
Then Pawit convinced me
to become a spirit host
to get me out of my slump.
The rest is history.
I want to be a spirit channeler
so that I can help people who are sad
feel better.
Wow.
Amazing.
- My turn. I'll ask the questions now.
- What?
I'll ask you some questions,
like Guru Asri did yesterday.
I'm terrified.
Where are you from?
Jakarta.
What did you do there?
I was an e-commerce employee.
Why are you always barefoot?
It's a fashion statement.
Why did you come to Latas village?
To build a hotel.
Liar, liar.
To heal.
Heal from what?
Trauma.
What kind of trauma?
I don't like these questions.
No. I can't tell you that yet.
Why not?
Because my voucher expired,
and I got hit with a rattan stick.
It hurt so much that it gave me amnesia.
Yeah. Why was I so stupid?
But did you overcome the trauma?
I've tried everything.
Alcohol, meditation…
I even got fancy and went to Bali.
Nothing worked.
Then my brother showed me a documentary
about trance parties and I was intrigued.
So I came here. I gave it a try.
And I liked it.
After a trance, I'm always relaxed.
Like after a yoga session.
- Did you grow a mustache too?
- What?
You mean if I became more masculine?
I mean like my friend, Yoga.
A channeler at Bondan's school.
- What the…
- He has a moustache.
That's so lame.
But he used to be barefoot
all the time as well.
- You're lame.
- His feet became mouldy.
I'm not joking.
I'd rub his feet clean every day.
Why? Just bring him here.
This place is a fish spa.
Fish spa? You're right.
But you…
Your brother's not here with you?
No. He's far away.
Hey, bring that raft back here!
- We need to cross.
- Okay. I'm sorry.
Good morning, people of Latas.
Good morning!
The Central School is conducting
a selection for our new spirit channeler.
Only six candidates remain
from the initial group of eight.
The spirit channeler
who gets selected today
will perform at the big party
at the end of the month.
Thank you, Mr. Budi and Mrs. Rina,
our hosts for Arif's circumcision party.
They were kind enough
to hold a trance party for us.
The hotel construction is just an excuse.
Wanaria wants our spring for this!
If that happens, we're doomed.
There'll be no water left
for our rice fields.
In the neighboring village,
everybody was forced to sell their land.
Now they have
a miserable life in the city.
- Latas is not for sale!
Wanaria Group is holding a music concert
to win people over.
But we know better.
This is where the real party is!
Yes!
See the blackboard behind me?
You all can vote here
for the best spirit channeler.
Our first channeler is Ananto
and his powerful fire ant spirit!
Eat, devour, enjoy!
My mother married my father in Dubai.
My father was a Dutch cook.
That's why I have a superior taste.
Today, I'm going to treat you all
to some great food from around the world.
But before that,
let's welcome our guest of honor.
Arif!
For our hors d'oeuvres,
raw bamboo shoots!
But thanks to the fire ant spirit,
these bamboo shoots will taste like…
croissants!
Our appetizer!
Sushi!
Main course!
Wagyu beef!
And for dessert…
Gelato!
Where are the crackers?
We can't have a meal without crackers.
You got it, my man! Get the plates out!
Don't overdo it. You're not ready.
Chill, ma'am.
Coffee! One more black coffee!
I got it.
Coffee, please.
- Not strong enough.
- Not strong enough?
Here come the crackers!
Crackling crackers crack!
Shit, this coffee is so strong.
Concentrate, don't lose them.
If you hurt them, you're screwed.
It's all right, ma'am.
I told you not to be cocky.
Look what happened.
Learn your limits.
Your heart can't take it.
Sorry, ma'am.
Who wants to go next?
Me.
The turtle spirit?
They're still bleeding and you
want to cane them with rattan sticks?
I didn't bring the turtle this time.
I just caught a new spirit.
Bedbugs?
Are you sure?
A bedbug is about to bite!
Rise and shine, look at it take flight!
Bayu, bring in the spirit hosts!
Bring in the bedbugs now!
Go back to being a human statue.
Beg on the streets.
Do you need this?
Guru Asri, the jumping mantra!
What do you call a bedbug?
The bouncing louse!
This is only half of the money.
We promise we'll pay you the rest soon.
We also have a gift for you.
A blanket for your grandson.
We hope he gets well soon.
Thank you, ma'am.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you, people of Latas.
The party has gone viral on social media.
They're calling it the Trance Mania.
Look at you jumping!
The bug princess from Jakarta.
Wasn't your niece born three months ago?
- Yes.
- She's a Leo, then.
I'm not into zodiac signs.
Leo is the lion. Find a lion.
- A lion?
- It represents the Leo sign.
Let's see. Do they even have a lion?
I found a tiger.
- That could work.
- Yeah.
Hey, get her this color.
The same as her element.
Get this one.
What's her element?
Fire, of course.
What's your star sign?
Guess.
You're a movie star.
You're so lame.
- I'll give you a clue.
- Let's see.
I was born in February.
- February.
- What is it?
I told you I'm not into that.
Look it up.
Hey, that's Mr. Banar.
He's a former spirit channeler.
One of the greatest.
Really?
He's a legend. I'll be right back.
- Mr. Banar.
- Hey.
- Mr. Banar, I'm a big fan.
- Okay.
- Can I take a selfie with you?
- Sure.
Cool.
- Your seahorse spirit was the best.
- You know that?
One, two, three.
It's raining! Thanks so much.
Oh, boy.
I'll take this one.
- It's 20,000.
- 20,000?
Yes.
- Here you go.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
- Yes.
Laksmi?
- Laksmi?
- Possess me.
It's raining.
- Do you have essential oil, ma'am?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Please possess me.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna touch your head, okay?
I'll give you a head massage.
We're in a public place,
so I can't put you in a trance.
Lean back. You'll feel better.
I once asked my brother to give me
a ride downtown to buy running shoes.
On the way, I kept telling him,
"Go faster. Hurry."
So he sped up.
Like a madman, in the rain.
We got into an accident…
and he died.
Every time it rains,
I am reminded of my foolishness.
I can't wear shoes anymore.
Can you help me go into a trance, Bayu?
I can't stand it when it rains.
Hello.
- How are you?
- I'm good.
- I got her a present.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- How long was the trip?
- About two hours.
- Where do I put this?
Over there.
Yono, our neighbor in Latas
just moved to Jakarta.
- Yeah.
- I heard Wanaria paid him a lot of money.
Did they make an offer on Mom's house too?
They did.
250 million rupiah.
What? That's a good offer.
Why didn't you tell me anything?
It's not that.
We were just negotiating.
Try to get 350 if you can.
I'll give it a try.
That's a good number to split into three.
One hundred for me, 100 for you,
and 100 for Wati.
You can use the rest of the money
to start a business here.
A friend of mine called Nana
asked me to start
a water-dispenser business with her.
Why don't you two just get married?
It's convenient.
Bayu can help you with the deliveries.
- That's not what I want.
- What?
I don't want you to sell the house.
I like living in Latas.
- How are you gonna earn a living there?
- Spirit-channeling.
I just got selected
by the best trance school in the village.
You still believe in that stuff?
People acting like tigers and shit,
isn't that just a scam?
Isn't there
a scientific explanation for that?
Like when you can't move your body
in your sleep?
Sleep paralysis.
More like "sleep paragliding."
That's why you have your head
in the clouds.
Bullshit.
- Bullshit.
Uncle Rahmat, Aunt Wati and Dad
used to go to trance parties all the time.
Just ask them.
What was your spirit, Dad? A frog?
A frog, that's funny.
That was when I was in grade school
and junior high.
I stopped after that.
But many of my friends are still doing it
even though they're old now.
It's not pretty.
Their lives are going nowhere.
Mr. Banar lives a good life now.
He has a nice car and a fancy phone.
Mr. Banar is not married.
You want to stay single your whole life?
But I ran into him
and his girlfriend yesterday.
But everyone in Latas
already sold their land.
Who will you put in a trance?
The bulldozers?
Tell them what you just got, son.
- A promotion.
- Yes.
See? You two are the same age, Bayu.
He has saved up
to get married and buy a house.
Next year.
- Are you planning to stay single forever?
- Whatever. I chose a different life.
Work is not all about marriage
and having children.
What do you mean?
I choose to do a job that can help people
and not just to fill up my own belly.
You're saying my job doesn't help people?
Just wait ten years.
See who gives more to charity.
- I didn't say that.
- You did.
What if in ten years
no one goes to those parties anymore?
You'll just be a burden
because you'd be jobless.
What I mean is,
people lead different lives.
Different things make them happy.
I've never burdened you,
so quit criticizing me.
You're living off my dad's money.
Then keep your money.
Enough! What's with the yelling?
You're too loud.
You always fight
whenever you see each other.
Watch that attitude.
Bayu, you shouldn't be like that
with our family.
It's not nice.
Why did you tell them?
You promised you wouldn't.
The house isn't mine alone.
We've talked about this.
I told you I'd pay for the house
in installments.
I got into the top four.
Just one more stage.
But there's no guarantee.
It'll take you forever to get the money.
Better to get the money slowly but surely,
than have you start a business
with Mrs. Nana and fail.
The debt collectors
will be on our asses again.
It's only been a day
and this city's already suffocating me.
Bayu!
Sorry about earlier.
I didn't mean to piss you off.
I got carried away.
We're going out to chill. Come join us!
No, thanks. I have to get back tonight.
What a party pooper!
Come on, just this once.
- Join us, Bayu!
- Come on!
Just go with them.
Humor them for once. They're family.
Uncle Rahmat has been so nice to us.
Hurry! We'll wait for you.
- Let's go!
- Come on!
Hey! Why are you so quiet?
Let's hit the floor.
I don't dance.
- What?
- I don't do this stuff.
You don't?
- Let me teach you some moves.
- Yeah. Show him!
Damn!
Drink up. It'll get you in the mood.
No, I don't drink this stuff.
He only gets drunk with cows.
Don't force him.
He prefers ritual offerings.
I bet this is how he parties
back in his village.
How?
Oh, shit!
Bull, bull!
My turn.
- So? What am I?
- A tiger!
Well? Was it good?
Yeah, it was good.
Look at Spiderman here, all lovey-dovey.
You're heavy, asshole.
Sorry, dude.
Not bad, but not as good as yesterday.
- What was on your mind?
- My relatives in Jakarta.
And?
They were making fun of what we do here.
They tried to make me drink.
And my uncle is trying to convince my dad
to sell the house.
By the way, while you were
getting drunk in Jakarta--
I didn't get drunk, ma'am!
The villagers proposed
a new spirit channeler.
- Hey, kid!
- Yes, ma'am!
- Come here.
- Excuse me.
Yes.
My man!
Get ready, you're up after Bayu.
The villagers want to see what you've got.
- What's your spirit?
- This, ma'am.
Whoa, okay. Get ready.
Ma'am, this isn't fair.
He wasn't even in the selection process,
and now he's leading the trance party?
- The other guys won't be happy either.
- Not happy?
That's what the villagers want.
What can I do?
Maybe he's been fasting
more than the others.
We'll see.
- Excuse me.
- Yes.
A drought affects Latas.
Let's bathe in the spirit realm.
Buffaloes locking their horns!
Drenched in rose-infused water
without thorns!
Soap!
Wash yourselves with soap!
Wash your hair!
Time to wash your hair!
Brush your teeth!
Dry yourselves!
Spray some cologne!
- Amazing!
- Careful.
Your trance effect is the best one so far.
So refreshing.
Not bad.
That was good!
Judges, we'll add Pawit's name
on the board.
Doni, Yuli, thanks for taking part
in this selection process.
All the best.
- Ma'am.
- Thanks.
Ma'am, you can't just do
whatever you want.
Whatever I want?
What we want
is for the villagers
to enjoy their lives in Latas.
So they're not forced
to sell their land to Wanaria.
We need the best spirit channeler.
If you can't get your mind off
your cousins in Jakarta,
maybe you should join them there.
Forget about being a channeler.
But if you think you're better
than the others, then prove it.
Get an upper-rank spirit for the final.
Horse.
Tiger.
Leech.
Bayu, I'm selling the house to Fahri.
Is that okay?
Come on, move to the city.
Trust me, it's the best.
If I get scammed again, we'll starve.
I'll need to steal another phone.
You can put the phone owner in a trance.
If they beat me up, put me in a trance.
Use the turtle spirit so I'm protected.
They're hitting your dad,
but it feels like a gentle massage.
I'm a tiger.
If I go to jail, you won't starve.
You're used to fasting.
In the city, you can get
the highest-ranked spirit. The cockroach.
I'm a leech.
You got the snake!
I'm kidding.
Hey, trance master,
what spirit are you trying to catch?
The worm? The caterpillar?
I see. You're not talking because
you're getting ready for the final, huh?
Guru Asri asked me to make
a new costume for the big party.
I'm her apprentice now.
You told me not to work for Wanaria.
Let me take your measurements.
Now's a good time.
You're in the right position.
Hey, why haven't you asked me
to practice with you again?
I miss it.
I miss going into a trance.
Want to do it later?
I brought you some chicken soup.
Bring Laksmi some chicken soup.
Guru Asri will choose Pawit
as the spirit channeler.
Laksmi will fall in love with Pawit
and marry him.
Laksmi and Pawit will have a child
and I'll be all alone.
They'll forget about me
and I'll be all alone until I'm old.
I'll die and they'll find me
after three days.
"With…"
"With Pawit," what?
But you're my practice partner.
So it has to be you.
A leech doesn't speak or eat.
A leech doesn't speak? But you just spoke.
What's with you? Did I do something wrong?
This is not fair to my student's family.
Sorry, ma'am, but I told you many times.
I have the deeds with me.
I have bought all these properties
through a realtor.
Where is this person?
I told you to bring him here.
The previous owner and my mom agreed
that this land would be a green space.
Why do you want to build here?
If this turns into housing,
all the rice fields will be gone!
Can you show me the written agreement?
His mother is a migrant worker in Qatar.
We can call her to discuss--
Do you know what time it is there?
It's 4:00 a.m. My mother's asleep!
Sure she's asleep? She could just be
coming back from her "job."
- Calm down!
- Eat shit!
Come here!
Bayu.
Bayu, we need help here.
Stop that.
They're trying to buy Ananto's rice field.
Tell them what Wanaria plans to do.
What did they say?
What's with you lately? Say something.
Bayu!
"I'm a leech. I'm a spirit channeler.
If Pawit wins, I'll sell my house."
"If Ananto wins, I'll go back to Jakarta."
"Laksmi's a distraction. I'm a leech.
If I win, I keep my home."
Are you mad?
Just because I'm now in the race
to become a spirit channeler?
That was up to Guru Asri.
I had nothing to do with it.
If you don't help us,
none of us will be spirit channelers.
Let me tend to your wounds.
Then we'll go practice,
I'll come with you.
Holy crap.
Does it have to be like this?
I know.
You're mad because I liked
Pawit's buffalo spirit, right?
That doesn't mean
your bedbug spirit is not good.
You said you wanted to become
a spirit channeler
because you love seeing people happy.
How can we be happy to see you like this?
The point of a trance party
is to have fun.
Not to torture yourself like this.
Bayu?
I am not going back to Jakarta.
Hear me out first.
I don't want to go back
to eating once every two days.
Uncle Rahmat and Aunt Wati have agreed.
I'm sick and tired
of all your businesses that go nowhere.
I wanted to tell you,
but you were gone for a week.
- Bayu?
- Mom left because of you!
I will put an end to all our misfortunes.
I apologize for not being
like other fathers.
I'm a failure.
That's why I'm not trying
to get in the way of your work here.
This house has been sold.
But I convinced your Uncle Rahmat…
not to sell the shed.
You can still live here.
You've already got what you wanted.
But I haven't.
Let me give it another try.
Don't disappear.
I'm a leech, I'm a leech.
A tiger crouching next to a strait!
Don't throw anyone as bait!
The rooster spirit.
The rooster defies death!
Until its very last breath!
The leech spirit.
Leeches of the forest survive!
Let's eat them alive!
The leech spirit will suck the blood
of all those who have hurt you.
Your father, your friend,
your significant other, your cousins.
Their blood will be drained
by the leech spirit!
Those who have provoked
inheritance disputes,
the leech will suck them dry.
Those childhood friends who hurt you,
the leech will eat them alive.
Neighbors, unfaithful partners,
scammers, thieves,
the leech will suck them dry.
The world will be a better place
without bad people.
if only good people remain!
The world will be a better place
if people don't hurt each other!
The leech will wipe them out!
Let's hear the final score.
Bayu.
Ananto.
And the final vote…
The results are in.
Bayu, two votes. Pawit, no votes.
Ananto, three votes.
We have a new spirit channeler.
Ananto Prasetya!
Even if it's hot like a boiling pot
Our prosperous Latas never disappoints
Our fields are yellow, full of worms
Our goats are healthy…
We haven't seen a leech spirit like yours
in 20 years.
We're very impressed
that you can channel it.
But it didn't make us happy.
Instead, it made us
want to kill the people we hate.
It wouldn't be right for this village.
PROPERTY OF WANARIA LLC
NO TRESPASSING
What spirit is it now?
Can I do it too?
I'm exhausted, too.
I know how you feel.
Abandoned by your father.
Being taken for granted.
Mr. Banar,
I failed to become a spirit channeler
because my father hurt me.
Calm down, Bayu.
To be a spirit channeler,
you have to have a big heart,
because our share of happiness
is meant for others.
I've fasted. I smell like an animal.
Just to be like you.
I don't mind
not having a wife or a family.
No family? Do you hear yourself?
All this time, haven't you ever wondered
why I always wear a jacket?
I'm thin as a skeleton,
but my belly weighs a ton.
You know about seahorses, right?
Female seahorses deposit their eggs
into the male's abdomen.
Sir.
Sir, don't.
If you failed yesterday, that means
you didn't really embody the spirit.
It's the male seahorses
that carry the babies.
I had to become a seahorse.
You think I don't have children?
This is my child.
It's been safe and sound inside my belly.
Everything has a price,
and that includes our own family.
Bayu.
I know your mind is foggy right now,
but I need your help.
Can you please put me in a trance?
It's raining.
You know how I get when it rains.
You can use this as your practice.
You gave this to me, remember?
Free trance anytime.
I need it now, Bayu.
I know. You have to suck my blood
like a leech now, right?
Drink my blood.
Fine. If you don't wanna help me,
I'll go into a trance myself.
- Leeches of the forest survive!
- Let's eat them alive!
Laksmi?
Laksmi!
- Help!
- Laksmi!
- Something has attacked the chicken farm!
Laksmi!
Laksmi.
Snap out of it, Laksmi.
I'll be there for you from now on.
Laksmi.
Now, Bayu!
Why are you so stubborn?
Still want to do everything alone?
It could kill her, you know that?
We found who slaughtered the chickens.
All units on site.
This is the second time, ma'am.
We did nothing wrong.
But your people keep on terrorizing us.
Calm down, let me explain…
Explain what? Look at this.
- Look.
- Okay, okay.
- We understand.
- We can see it.
We have eyes. Back off.
I talked to the Wanaria representatives.
They lost about 20 million rupiah
because of what happened.
Can you pay for it?
I can.
I'm sorry for all the trouble I caused.
It's fine.
You can stay here and rest.
And as for you, Bayu…
A butterfly perches on a horn.
You try to catch it, and it flies away.
You search for gold until you're torn.
Once it's in your hands…
your loved ones slip away.
I shouldn't have forced you
to redeem my voucher.
Come to think of it,
my brother died because of a voucher.
Just a 20% discount from the shoe store.
I have enough shoes at home.
I wish I'd known
what "enough" meant back then.
My brother would be alive now.
I should be responsible
for making you happy.
It's my fault.
I should've known that you were sad
because your dad sold the house.
He never learns. He's too stubborn.
Nothing's ever good enough for him.
Well, maybe…
he feels good enough with himself,
but he doesn't feel good enough
to be your dad.
LAND OWNERSHIP CERTIFICATE
CONGRATULATIONS TO OUR NEW MEMBERS
I want you to know something.
When you were putting me in a trance,
I felt happy.
So you have to believe in yourself.
You're a good spirit channeler.
Good luck.
Wow, new flute!
New flute.
It's from my dad.
He made it with a water pipe.
The day has finally come.
Welcome to Latas Village's
grand trance party!
All the profits from today
will be used to buy the spring
from Mr. Dawuri.
After conducting a selection process
in eight schools in Latas,
I'd like to introduce you
to the new spirit channeler.
He'll be leading today's party.
With you, Ananto Prasetya!
Let's go, Ananto!
And his two assistants,
Pawit Arifin and Bayu Laksana!
The tiger's out for lunch!
Don't hold back, land a punch!
What are those security guards doing here?
Who's that guy? Do you know him?
Help!
- A host attacked a man!
- Lies!
- We have it on video.
- He's not in a trance!
A host attacked a villager!
Don't touch the hosts!
Hosts, do not attack!
One of the hosts attacked a villager.
There's video evidence.
They are causing a disturbance!
All villagers, please evacuate the area.
One of the hosts attacked a villager!
Go! Go! Go!
All villagers, please evacuate the area.
One of the hosts attacked a villager!
This parties have caused disturbances
over and over again!
- Please evacuate the area!
- How dare you? This is all a lie!
All villagers, please evacuate the area.
One of the hosts attacked a villager!
This parties have caused disturbances
over and over again!
Please evacuate the area!
All villagers, please evacuate the area.
Guru Asri, sing the turtle mantra!
Pawit and Ananto, get all the hosts!
Turtle self-protection forevermore!
Protected at the core!
Guru Asri, the massage realm!
Bayu, get everyone in!
The rattan stick, Bayu!
Protect their backs!
Laksmi, forgive me for walking out on you.
Ananto, I'm sorry
for treating you as a rival.
Pawit, thank you
for always being there for me.
Ma'am, thank you for always guiding me.
People of Latas,
forgive me for being selfish.
Human statue from my past,
thank you for going through all that.
Thank you for pushing forward.
The turtle's shell withstands the stick!
Ananto, the ant spirit!
Pawit, form the host circle!
Are you sure?
Ants scurrying all around!
Get tangled in your hair
and move all round!
Bayu! The fire ant spirit
will see the security guards as prey!
You want to attack them?
No, nobody will hurt anyone!
You could use the leech spirit.
Destroy all those security guards,
suck them dry.
They deserve it.
No, no, no.
Not like that.
Bayu, he might not be a bad person.
Maybe he's just following orders.
He might not harbor hatred in his heart.
Maybe he has a family to feed.
He might not be a murderer.
Maybe he has a sick father at home.
They just need to be hugged.
This guy might not be a bad man after all.
Maybe he just needs to prove something.
Maybe he's been hurt.
Taken for granted, like me.
Maybe he feels he's not good enough.
Dad has always been alone.
He was jailed and beaten up
because he stole a phone.
After we both starved,
his wife walked out on him.
He kept getting scammed.
His plant business failed.
His gemstone business failed.
His betta fish business failed.
Dad did all of that for me.
Maybe he felt good about himself,
but he hasn't felt good enough as my dad.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Thank you. You're not alone.
I can't hold it anymore!
Monkey spirit!
Remember your training for the monkey hug!
- A monkey eats a banana under a rug!
- Come on, get them in a group hug!
We're already waiting by the gate.
Please wait.
Ten people are heading up.
They'll be there in five minutes.
Copy that.
I'd like to use this opportunity
to make it clear
that the Wanaria group had nothing to do
with the incident that occurred
during yesterday's trance party.
We never gave such orders
and we condemn the perpetrators.
We believe some individuals from our old
security company were involved
in personal disputes with the villagers.
We at the Wanaria Group
have terminated our contract
with the security agency involved.
We have also recruited
a new security agency.
We want to preserve the culture
of trance parties in Latas Village.
Why? So that local tourists
and foreign tourists can come here.
We're also considering promoting it
as an international attraction.
Liar! Liar!
- Wanaria was behind it all along!
- We want the truth!
We are grateful.
The spring didn't fall
into Wanaria's hands.
But we have to realize
that our fight is far from over.
Wanaria is still here!
And what we are doing here
is a form of resistance against them.
Bayu, do you want some tea,
coffee, or orange juice?
Water's fine.
So Ananto was chosen
as the spirit channeler?
Yes. But it's okay. In the end,
they didn't do anything to his rice field.
It's all right. You'll get another chance.
Yes.
How's the house?
Good. They left our side yard intact.
Due to the incident, some restaurateurs
looking to invest changed their minds.
They just left.
All right.
These are Mrs. Nana's children.
Hello.
- Hello.
- Hey.
- Uncle, we'll go play soccer.
- Okay, be careful.
Okay.
They're calling you uncle now?
They're not used to calling me dad yet.
So what spirit do you have now?
- The lizard.
- Wow.
Just got it yesterday.
The lizard is cool. Upper rank.
Do you want to try it?
What do you mean?
The lizard spirit.
The last time you were a host
was 20, 30 years ago?
It's been 35 years.
That's like forever.
Want to try it? I got my flute with me.
I'm still here for the weekend.
I'll go back to Latas on Monday.
"SKR" DRINKING WATER
HIGH-QUALITY REFILLS
I'll skip the soup.
Better to do this on an empty stomach.
Shall we?